Ottawa, Ontario, Canada zaid.qureshi94@gmail.com www.zaid.work

About Zaid

Software Engineering student at the University of Ottawa, with a strong interest in mobile and web development. Always working on new projects with passion to explore software technologies. My experience includes, but not limited to, web development, Android development, and quality assurance.

Education

BASc in Software Engineering with Engineering Management University of Ottawa

2012 to April 2016 (expected)

■ Currently in fourth year

Areas of Expertise

- Advanced Java (Android) and C++ Programming:
- + Developed Android Application with 40000+ downloads
- + Developed mobile payments application for Telepin Software
- + Developed a file transfer system over LAN
- + Tutored for Java
- Advanced Knowledge of Ruby on Rails framework:
- + Developed TutorStaff.com
- Advanced Knowledge of C, Python, AngularJS, PHP, JavaScript
- Advanced use of Databases:
- + Designed secure database systems
- + Developed a Radio Station Application
- + Used MySQL, PostgreSQL, and Oracle SQL

Experience

Cloud Developer

September 2015 to present

Clearwater Clinical

- Develop innovative mobile medical solutions
- Work with Amazon Web Services
- Build distributed, scalable, and highly available applications
- Writing a RESTful API
- Unit testing and automated testing

Mobile Application Developer

Telepin Software

- Developed android and cross-platform mobile application for mobile payments
- Designed 3 tier architecture server
- Automated scripts for Testing Android, web applications, and USSD menus
- Wrote documentation on Confluence for technical and non-technical personnels
- Atlassian Jira used for issue tracking

May 2014 to April 2015

Android Application Developer

Self-Employed

- Create user friendly, and effcient applications
- Developed 40 Rabbana Duas, 40000+ downloads
- Developed Escape, 700+ downloads
- Developed Line Maze
- Playstore developer name: zaid.qureshi

Computer Science Tutor

Self-Employed

- Helped students understand basic and advanced programming concepts
- Came up with exercises for the students
- Provided efficient solutions for the problems students face

Academic Director

Software Engineering Student Association (uOttawa)

- Helped students with problems in their courses
- Helped arrange tech-talks
- Provided students with exercises to help improve their programming skills

IT Specialist Intern

Wiconnect Corp.

- Provided IT support remotely to clients, at client locations
- Repaired or replaced different parents in laptops or desktops
- Finished tasks within given time period, satisfied client needs
- Assist IT specialists with their tasks

Concepts

Analysis and Design of User Interfaces

- Knowledge of evaluating user interfaces, usability engineering, task analysis
- Experience in user-centered design and prototyping.

Design and Analysis of Algorithms

- Analysis of algorithms: worst-case analysis, complexity analysis, asymptotic notations and basic complexity classes
- Algorithm design techniques: brute force, divide and conquer, dynamic programming, greedy, backtracking
- Computational complexity of problems: lower bound arguments, the classes P, NP, NP-complete, dealing with NP-complete problems

Data Structures:

- Advanced knowledge of balanced trees, binary-trees, hashing
- Practiced sorting of Graphs and simple graph algorithms: traversal, minimum spanning tree
- Worked with java collections library such as linkedlists iterators etc
- Performed analysis of recursive programs using recurrence relations
- Studied properties of integers and basic cryptographical applications

References

Please email for more contact information and references.

January 2013 to Present

January 2013 to Present

September 2014 to Present

June 2013 to July 2013